<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on SIEMForge</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on SIEMForge</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 10:17:23 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://siemforge.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My first automation workflow</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/automation/n8n/firstautomationworkflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 10:17:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/automation/n8n/firstautomationworkflow/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-first-steps-into-automation-with-ai-agents-using-n8n">My first steps into automation with AI agents using n8n&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="setting-the-stage-n8n-in-my-homelab">Setting the stage: n8n in my homelab&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As someone constantly tinkering in my &lt;strong>Proxmox-based homelab&lt;/strong>, I recently decided to explore &lt;strong>workflow automation with AI agents&lt;/strong> using &lt;a href="https://n8n.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">n8n&lt;/a> — a powerful, self-hostable automation tool that connects anything to everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get started, I spun up a new container and installed &lt;strong>n8n via Portainer&lt;/strong>, running it in Docker. For anyone looking to do the same, here&amp;rsquo;s the official n8n install guide for Docker and Portainer:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Logrotate</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/linux/logrotate/logrotate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 14:17:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/linux/logrotate/logrotate/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mastering-logrotate-the-unsung-hero-of-log-management">Mastering Logrotate: The Unsung Hero of Log Management&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In the trenches of system administration, there&amp;rsquo;s one silent guardian that keeps your disk space from imploding under a mountain of logs: &lt;strong>Logrotate&lt;/strong>. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re wrangling logs on a sprawling Kubernetes cluster or just babysitting a single Linux box, Logrotate ensures your logs don’t spiral out of control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this deep dive, we’ll explore how Logrotate works, why it’s essential, how to configure it like a pro, and how to troubleshoot when it throws a tantrum.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>