<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on SIEMForge</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on SIEMForge</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:17:23 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://siemforge.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenTofu Project: Proxmox foundations</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/orchestration/opentofu/opentofu1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:17:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/orchestration/opentofu/opentofu1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="securing-the-hypervisor-before-anything-else"&gt;Securing the hypervisor before anything else&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-hypervisor-security-comes-first"&gt;Why hypervisor security comes first&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any virtualization environment, the hypervisor represents a high-value target. A compromised virtual machine is an incident. A compromised hypervisor is a catastrophe. Before building labs, automating infrastructure, or experimenting with offensive security techniques, it is essential to establish a hardened Proxmox VE baseline. This article walks through securing a single-node Proxmox installation as the foundation for a security-focused lab.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tech report: Cato Networks log ingestion</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/siem/tech-reports/techreportcatonetworks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:17:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/siem/tech-reports/techreportcatonetworks/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="executive-summary"&gt;Executive summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cato Networks logs stopped ingesting into Splunk following a customer-initiated unannounced maintenance. Investigation revealed that the API connection for log retrieval was interrupted, requiring manual intervention to restore service. The incident highlighted the impact of uncoordinated maintenance activities on log ingestion stability. Immediate checks were performed on the Heavy Forwarder logs, and the scripted input was reset to restore log flow. No other log sources were found to be affected at this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SIEM data onboarding</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/siem/data-onboarding/dataonboardingpost/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:17:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/siem/data-onboarding/dataonboardingpost/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="siem-data-onboarding-best-practices-and-a-deepdive-into-splunk-vs-microsoft-sentinel"&gt;SIEM data onboarding: Best practices and a deepdive into Splunk vs Microsoft Sentinel&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="executive-summary"&gt;Executive summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security Information and Event Management (SIEM) platforms are only as effective as the data they receive. SIEM data onboarding is the process of getting the right logs, in the right format, into the SIEM so it can detect threats, support incident response, and demonstrate compliance. Simply “sending some logs” is not enough; quality, completeness, and normalization drive the value you get from your SIEM investment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>TCPDump</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/linux/tcpdump/tcpdumppost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 10:25:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/linux/tcpdump/tcpdumppost/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="tcpdump-intro-for-linux-engineers"&gt;TCPDump intro for Linux engineers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a SIEM platform administrator, one of the most invaluable tools in my troubleshooting arsenal is tcpdump. It allows the user to display TCP/IP and other packets being transmitted or received over a network. Despite its simplicity, it is incredibly powerful for debugging complex network issues, monitoring traffic, or simply learning how different protocols behave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-use-tcpdump"&gt;Why use tcpdump&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-time packet inspection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightweight and scriptable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No need for a GUI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful for security auditing and troubleshooting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-to-install-tcpdump"&gt;How to install tcpdump&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Debian/Ubuntu-based systems:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>LVM</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/linux/lvm/lvmpost/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 07:17:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/linux/lvm/lvmpost/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="first-start-with-lvm-logical-volume-manager"&gt;First start with LVM (Logical Volume Manager)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-lvm"&gt;What is LVM?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LVM stands for &lt;strong&gt;Logical Volume Manager&lt;/strong&gt;, a device mapper framework that provides logical volume management for the Linux kernel. LVM allows administrators to create, resize, and delete volumes dynamically, offering more flexibility than traditional partitioning schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-use-lvm"&gt;Why use LVM?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic resizing&lt;/strong&gt;: Easily resize (extend/reduce) logical volumes without unmounting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snapshot support&lt;/strong&gt;: Create point-in-time snapshots for backup or testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume grouping&lt;/strong&gt;: Aggregate multiple physical devices into a single storage pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migration&lt;/strong&gt;: Move volumes across physical devices live.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;: Logical volumes can span across multiple disks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lvm-architecture"&gt;LVM architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://siemforge.xyz/images/posts/lvm.png" alt="LVM Architecture"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My first automation workflow</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/automation/n8n/firstautomationworkflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 10:17:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/automation/n8n/firstautomationworkflow/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-first-steps-into-automation-with-ai-agents-using-n8n"&gt;My first steps into automation with AI agents using n8n&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="setting-the-stage-n8n-in-my-homelab"&gt;Setting the stage: n8n in my homelab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone constantly tinkering in my &lt;strong&gt;Proxmox-based homelab&lt;/strong&gt;, I recently decided to explore &lt;strong&gt;workflow automation with AI agents&lt;/strong&gt; using &lt;a href="https://n8n.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;n8n&lt;/a&gt; — a powerful, self-hostable automation tool that connects anything to everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, I spun up a new container and installed &lt;strong&gt;n8n via Portainer&lt;/strong&gt;, running it in Docker. For anyone looking to do the same, here&amp;rsquo;s the official n8n install guide for Docker and Portainer:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Logrotate</title><link>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/linux/logrotate/logrotatepost/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 14:17:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://siemforge.xyz/posts/linux/logrotate/logrotatepost/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mastering-logrotate-the-unsung-hero-of-log-management"&gt;Mastering Logrotate: The unsung hero of log management&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the trenches of system administration, there&amp;rsquo;s one silent guardian that keeps your disk space from imploding under a mountain of logs: &lt;strong&gt;Logrotate&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re wrangling logs on a sprawling Kubernetes cluster or just babysitting a single Linux box, Logrotate ensures your logs don’t spiral out of control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll explore how Logrotate works, why it’s essential, how to configure it like a pro, and how to troubleshoot when it throws a tantrum.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>